Y.Bapu Reddy () Featured

Software Engineer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution Architecture, Angular, Java, J2EE, Rest Full Web Services, C, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node JS, Spring MVC



Current Designation: Software Developer Total Experience: 5 Year(s) 1 Month(s)

Current Company: Techmahindra Pvt LTD Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E.

Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad [Electronics/Telecommunication]

Pref. Location: Hyderabad

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Engineer, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution Architecture, Angular, Java, J2EE, Rest Full Web

Services, C, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node JS, Spring MVC

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Summary

I have 3+ years of IT Experience in Software industry in development of Multitier applications using Angular, Java. Working as Techno Functional and Performance Engineer in Amdocs Intelecable project's product development team. Experience in UI design and development using Angular, JavaScript, HTML, CSS. Experience in analysis and development of client and server, Web Applications using Angular. Solid knowledge on OOPs, Java SE, Java EE, Collection framework, Exception handling, Spring framework. Have keen interest in upgrading my skill set and ready to take up new challenges and Roles. Smart worker, Quick learner and excellent team player with strong interpersonal skills.

Work Experience

Techmahindra Pvt LTD as Software Developer Mar 2017 to Till Date

Angular and java developer

Tech Mahindra as Software Engineer -Java Mar 2017 to Mar 2017

Tata Consultancy Services Ltd. as Software Engineer Feb 2015 to May 2016

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from JNTU College of Engineering, Hyderabad in 2014

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
Angular, Java			
Rest full web services, C			
HTML, CSS			
JavaScript			
Embedded C			
Load Runner 12.53			
ORACLE 12C			
Node JS			
Eclipse			
ANT, Jenkins			
Web logic 12.1.3			
WINDOWS, LINUX			
SVN			
CAN, TCP and UDP			
DOORS, INTEGRITY, Raphsody			

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Telugu				

Projects

Project Title: BMW Airbag Software Test

Client: TRW AUTOMOTIVE -Germany (Radolfzell)

Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Sep 2015 - Till Date
Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Skill Used: C

Project Details: The Airbag Electronic Control Unit system controls the Airbag Deployment in the Automobiles. This project presents a new approach for ECU software development/testing in absence of target hardware in real time. Used Cantata++ tool for this testing. Using this approach SW is tested at unit/module (ENG.6) and functional testing in SPICE model. Test results are documented and provided to the customer through Version Manager. Few of the Modules Tested at (ENG6 level) I.e., at module level are System Messages, PADStatus, Operating Hour Counter, (ENG.7 level) I.e, at Extented ECU Identification. (ENG8 level) I.e System level are PADStatus.

Project Title: V&V for Toyota Airbag

Client: TRW

Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Nov 2014 - Till Date
Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Skill Used: C

Project Details: Airbag system is a safety critical control system that resides inside a Car and is primarily responsible for passenger protection during a crash event. The airbag unit acquires data from special sensors and when a crash condition is detected, deploys airbags and pensioners to protect the passengers in the car. The central "Airbag control unit" (ACU), a specific type of ECU, monitors a number of related sensors within the vehicle, determines the angle of impact, the severity, or force of the crash, along with other variables. Depending on the result of these calculations, the ACU deploy the airbags

1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=5757040128bc05264d30b75075f4ff990a555a5448175d445243150c5b...

including frontal bags for driver and front passenger, along with seat-mounted side bags, and curtain airbags which cover the side glass.

Job Type: Permanent

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Employment Status: Full time